<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HydraEarth</title>
    <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HydraEarth</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-mission&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Our Mission&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#our-mission&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HydraEarth Network is dedicated to creating equitable access to green workforce opportunities while addressing critical environmental challenges through education, training, and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-platform&#34;&gt;&#xA;  About the Platform&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#about-the-platform&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This website serves as a hub for showcasing HydraEarth’s research, initiatives, and data-driven insights that advance climate equity and sustainable innovation. Through interactive dashboards, visual reports, and collaborative projects, we highlight how technology, education, and community action intersect to build a more inclusive green future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversidade e equidade na força de trabalho - 1-1</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_1_demographic.pt_br/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_1_demographic.pt_br/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- tags = [&#xA;    &#34;hugo&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;markdown&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;emoji&#34;,&#xA;]&#xA;categories = [&#xA;    &#34;sintaxe&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;demonstração do tema&#34;,&#xA;] --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;composição-demográfica-da-força-de-trabalho-do-setor-de-energia-limpa&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Composição demográfica da força de trabalho do setor de energia limpa&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#composi%c3%a7%c3%a3o-demogr%c3%a1fica-da-for%c3%a7a-de-trabalho-do-setor-de-energia-limpa&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resumo&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Resumo&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#resumo&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Este estudo enfoca a diversidade e a equidade da força de trabalho no setor de energia limpa dos EUA, combinando dados brutos do USEER 2024 com fontes externas (ACS PUMS, BLS, McKinsey, etc.) para examinar quem trabalha na indústria de energia limpa, se recebem remuneração justa e o impacto da diversidade no desempenho da indústria. Nossa análise revela:&#xA;Representatividade: Existem disparidades significativas na composição racial e de gênero do setor de energia limpa, com certos grupos (como mulheres, latinos e negros) ainda significativamente sub-representados em áreas emergentes como energia solar e eólica, em comparação com a média nacional.&#xA;Equidade e diferença salarial: uma análise preliminar indica que as diferenças salariais entre gêneros e raças persistem e até aumentam no emprego em energia limpa, com alguns campos técnicos apresentando disparidades mais pronunciadas.&#xA;Impacto no desempenho: a diversidade não é apenas uma questão de justiça, mas também um fator-chave no retorno sobre o investimento e na competitividade. Pesquisas e estudos de caso indicam que o aumento da diversidade pode melhorar significativamente a lucratividade da empresa, as taxas de retenção e as pontuações ESG.&#xA;Essas descobertas não apenas fornecem aos formuladores de políticas insights para a tomada de decisões baseadas em dados, mas também servem como uma narrativa e uma proposta de valor comercial para empresas e investidores promoverem a equidade na força de trabalho.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introdução&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introdução&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#introdu%c3%a7%c3%a3o&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;À medida que a transição energética dos EUA se acelera, o setor de energia limpa está se expandindo rapidamente. No entanto, neste mercado de trabalho emergente, questões de diversidade e equidade salarial permanecem sem solução. Mulheres e minorias têm sido historicamente sub-representadas em ocupações relacionadas a STEM e energia, e as diferenças salariais são generalizadas.&#xA;Este estudo tem como objetivo analisar sistematicamente o estado atual da diversidade e equidade no emprego em energia limpa e abordar três questões centrais:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quem-trabalha-no-setor-de-energia-limpa&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Quem trabalha no setor de energia limpa?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#quem-trabalha-no-setor-de-energia-limpa&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quais são as taxas de participação de diferentes grupos étnicos, gêneros e faixas etárias em setores como energia solar, eólica, eficiência e veículos? Existem diferenças de representatividade em comparação com as médias nacionais?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eles-recebem-salários-iguais&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Eles recebem salários iguais?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#eles-recebem-sal%c3%a1rios-iguais&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Depois de controlar fatores como educação e setor, ainda existem diferenças salariais significativas entre gêneros e raças? Quais setores ou tecnologias apresentam as diferenças mais pronunciadas?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;por-que-isso-é-importante&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Por que isso é importante?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#por-que-isso-%c3%a9-importante&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Como a diversidade afeta a produtividade, a lucratividade, a retenção de funcionários e as pontuações ESG? É possível estabelecer uma narrativa clara de retorno sobre o investimento (ROI)?&#xA;Usando dados brutos do USEER + dados salariais do ACS PUMS + evidências de pesquisas externas, este estudo não apenas descreve o panorama da diversidade no emprego em energia limpa, mas também fornece recomendações práticas e propostas de valor comercial para apoiar o avanço de políticas e a tomada de decisões corporativas.&#xA;Impacto no desempenho: a diversidade não é apenas uma questão de justiça, mas também um fator-chave no retorno sobre o investimento e na competitividade. Pesquisas e estudos de caso indicam que o aumento da diversidade pode melhorar significativamente a lucratividade da empresa, as taxas de retenção e as pontuações ESG.&#xA;Essas descobertas não apenas fornecem aos formuladores de políticas insights para a tomada de decisões baseadas em dados, mas também servem como uma narrativa e uma proposta de valor comercial para empresas e investidores promoverem a equidade na força de trabalho.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;visual-2-força-de-trabalho-em-energia-limpa-por-gênero-participação-em-&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Visual 2: Força de trabalho em energia limpa por gênero (participação em %)&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#visual-2-for%c3%a7a-de-trabalho-em-energia-limpa-por-g%c3%aanero-participa%c3%a7%c3%a3o-em-&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Esta figura apresenta a distribuição por gênero no mesmo conjunto de tecnologias usado na linha de base de raça/etnia (energia solar, eólica, nuclear EPG, gás natural EPG, hidrelétrica de baixo impacto, hidrelétrica tradicional e eficiência energética). Subdividimos as tabelas de características da força de trabalho da USEER nas categorias Masculino, Feminino e Gênero não binário e, em seguida, calculamos a participação média (%) de cada tecnologia por gênero. Para garantir a comparabilidade com o gráfico anterior, as tecnologias foram alinhadas ao índice pivot_race. As barras são rotuladas com valores percentuais (uma casa decimal) para facilitar comparações semelhantes entre as tecnologias.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A altura de cada barra indica a participação média desse gênero na força de trabalho da tecnologia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As etiquetas nas barras (por exemplo, “xx,x%”) fornecem valores exatos, reduzindo a ambiguidade quando as barras estão visualmente próximas. Como usamos participações, as diferenças entre as tecnologias refletem a composição, não o tamanho do quadro de funcionários.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Principais conclusões&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Os trabalhadores do sexo masculino constituem a maioria em todas as tecnologias, com as maiores proporções masculinas normalmente observadas em segmentos intensivos em construção e operações (por exemplo, EGP eólica, EGP nuclear, EGP de gás natural).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As participações não binárias de gênero parecem pequenas, mas não nulas em várias tecnologias; dada a baixa prevalência, essas estimativas devem ser interpretadas com cautela amostra potencial&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A representação feminina é relativamente maior nas áreas de eficiência energética e energia solar, embora ainda esteja abaixo da paridade na maioria dos casos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A participação de pessoas não binárias parece pequena, mas não nula em várias tecnologias; dada a baixa prevalência, essas estimativas devem ser interpretadas com cautela (possíveis efeitos de amostragem e arredondamento).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpretação e contexto&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;O padrão está alinhado com a segregação ocupacional observada nas cadeias de valor da energia e da construção — instalação, O&amp;amp;M e funções de campo são predominantemente masculinas, enquanto os segmentos com maiores proporções de gerenciamento de projetos, vendas e divulgação apresentam proporções femininas ligeiramente mais altas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Essas diferenças de composição fornecem um contexto importante para a análise da diferença salarial nas seções 3.3–3.5: se as trabalhadoras estão sub-representadas nas tecnologias ou funções mais bem remuneradas, as diferenças salariais agregadas podem refletir tanto efeitos de preço (salários diferentes para funções semelhantes) quanto efeitos de combinação (funções/tecnologias diferentes).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Principais conclusões&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A energia solar e a eficiência energética apresentam normalmente diferenças negativas menores ou diferenças positivas modestas, indicando que a participação da comunidade BIPOC está mais próxima (ou ligeiramente acima) das médias nacionais nestes segmentos de crescimento inicial.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;O EPG nuclear e o EPG de gás natural geralmente apresentam diferenças negativas maiores, sinalizando uma sub-representação dos trabalhadores BIPOC em tecnologias de alta remuneração e intensivas em capital.&#xA;A energia hidrelétrica (tradicional e de baixo impacto) tende a ficar próxima ou ligeiramente abaixo da paridade, mas os padrões podem variar de acordo com a folha/agregação.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interpretação e implicações&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;O padrão sugere segmentação do pipeline: os trabalhadores BIPOC estão mais presentes em funções de crescimento de instalação/eficiência/frente do medidor (por exemplo, energia solar, EE), mas estão sub-representados em tecnologias legadas, com salários mais altos ou que exigem muitas licenças (por exemplo, energia nuclear, gás natural).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onde a diferença é negativa e grande, o setor provavelmente enfrenta barreiras à entrada e ao avanço (credenciamento, triagem de experiência prévia, vias de acesso ao sindicato ou agrupamento geográfico). Estas são áreas prioritárias para intervenções de equidade (por exemplo, estágios, ponte de credenciais, recrutamento direcionado e patrocínio/mentoria).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;visual-3-diferença-de-representação-do-bipoc-em-relação-à-média-da-força-de-trabalho-nacional&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Visual 3: Diferença de representação do BIPOC em relação à média da força de trabalho nacional&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#visual-3-diferen%c3%a7a-de-representa%c3%a7%c3%a3o-do-bipoc-em-rela%c3%a7%c3%a3o-%c3%a0-m%c3%a9dia-da-for%c3%a7a-de-trabalho-nacional&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diferença de representação (BIPOC) por tecnologia, pontos percentuais (pp). Esta figura quantifica como o BIPOC (todos os grupos não brancos combinados) está representado em cada tecnologia de energia limpa em relação à média da força de trabalho nacional dos EUA. Valores positivos indicam sobrerrepresentação (a participação do BIPOC nessa tecnologia excede a média nacional); valores negativos indicam sub-representação.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Emojis podem ser ativados em um projeto Hugo de diversar formas. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity &amp; Workforce Equity - 1-1</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_1_demographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_1_demographic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- tags = [&#xA;    &#34;hugo&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;markdown&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;emoji&#34;,&#xA;] &#xA;&#xA;categories = [&#xA;    &#34;syntax&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;theme demo&#34;,&#xA;]--&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;demographic-composition-of-the-clean-energy-workforce&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Demographic Composition of the Clean Energy Workforce&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#demographic-composition-of-the-clean-energy-workforce&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Abstract&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study focuses on diversity and workforce equity in the U.S. clean energy sector, combining USEER 2024 raw data with external sources (ACS PUMS, BLS, McKinsey, etc.) to examine who works in the clean energy industry, whether they receive fair compensation, and the impact of diversity on industry performance. Our analysis reveals:&#xA;Representation: There are significant disparities in the racial and gender composition of the clean energy sector, with certain groups (such as women, Latinos, and Blacks) still significantly underrepresented in emerging fields like Solar and Wind compared to the national average.&#xA;Equity &amp;amp; Pay Gap: Preliminary proxy analysis indicates that gender and racial pay gaps persist and even widen in clean energy employment, with some technical fields showing more pronounced disparities.&#xA;Performance Impact: Diversity is not only a fairness issue but also a key factor in ROI and competitiveness. Research and case studies indicate that increasing diversity can significantly improve company profitability, retention rates, and ESG scores.&#xA;These findings not only provide policymakers with data-driven decision-making insights but also serve as a narrative and business value proposition for companies and investors to advance workforce equity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the U.S. energy transition accelerates, the clean energy sector is expanding rapidly. However, in this emerging job market, issues of diversity and wage equity remain unresolved. Women and minorities have historically been underrepresented in STEM and energy-related occupations, and wage gaps are widespread.&#xA;This study aims to systematically analyze the current state of diversity and equity in clean energy employment and address three core questions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-is-in-clean-energy-jobs&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Who is in clean energy jobs?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#who-is-in-clean-energy-jobs&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are the participation rates of different ethnic groups, genders, and age groups in sectors such as solar, wind, efficiency, and vehicles? Are there representation gaps compared to national averages?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-they-paid-equally&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Are they paid equally?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#are-they-paid-equally&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After controlling for factors such as education and industry, do significant gender and racial wage gaps still exist? Which industries or technologies exhibit the most pronounced gaps?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-does-it-matter&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Why does it matter?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#why-does-it-matter&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How does diversity impact productivity, profitability, employee retention, and ESG scores? Can a clear return on investment (ROI) narrative be established?&#xA;Using USEER raw data + ACS PUMS wage data + external research evidence, this study not only outlines the diversity landscape of clean energy employment but also provides actionable recommendations and business value propositions to support policy advancement and corporate decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;visual-1-raceethnicity-distribution-by-technology-stacked-bar-with-labels&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Visual 1: Race/Ethnicity Distribution by Technology (Stacked Bar with Labels)&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#visual-1-raceethnicity-distribution-by-technology-stacked-bar-with-labels&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis presents the baseline demographic composition of the clean energy workforce across selected technologies. A stacked bar chart was constructed to display the proportional representation of major racial and ethnic groups within key technologies, including Solar, Wind, Nuclear, Natural Gas, Hydropower (low-impact and traditional), and Energy Efficiency. The results reveal clear disparities across technologies:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White workers consistently form the largest share, particularly in Nuclear and Natural Gas sectors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hispanic or Latino workers are notably concentrated in Solar and Energy Efficiency, suggesting industry-specific clustering.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black or African American workers are underrepresented across most technologies, with relatively higher shares only in select subsectors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Asian workers have a stronger presence in high-skill, capital-intensive sectors such as Nuclear.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Representation of Indigenous, Pacific Islander, and multi-racial groups remains limited, with each generally below 5%.&#xA;To ensure readability, labels were placed directly within each stacked segment for groups exceeding 3% share, providing both visual clarity and precise numeric context. This visualization serves as a baseline benchmark for understanding racial and ethnic representation in the clean energy workforce. It highlights both areas of diversity and persistent gaps, which form the foundation for subsequent analyses of gender differences, wage disparities, and structural inequities in later sections.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;visual-2-clean-energy-workforce-by-gender-share-&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Visual 2: Clean Energy Workforce by Gender (Share %)&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#visual-2-clean-energy-workforce-by-gender-share-&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This figure presents the gender distribution across the same set of technologies used in the race/ethnicity baseline (Solar, Wind, Nuclear EPG, Natural Gas EPG, Low-impact Hydropower, Traditional Hydropower, and Energy Efficiency). We subset the USEER workforce-characteristics tables to the categories Male, Female, and Gender non-binary, then computed each technology’s average share (%) by gender. To ensure comparability with the prior chart, technologies were aligned to the pivot_race index. Bars are labeled with percentage values (one decimal place) to facilitate like-for-like comparisons across technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The height of each bar indicates the average share of that gender within the technology’s workforce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On-bar labels (e.g., “xx.x%”) provide exact values, reducing ambiguity where bars are visually close. Because we use shares, cross-technology differences reflect composition, not headcount size.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key findings&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Male workers constitute the majority across all technologies, with the highest male shares typically observed in construction- and operations-intensive segments (e.g., Wind, Nuclear EPG, Natural Gas EPG).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Female representation is relatively higher in Energy Efficiency and Solar, though still below parity in most cases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gender non-binary shares appear small but non-zero in several technologies; given low prevalence, these estimates should be interpreted cautiously (potential sample and rounding effects).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation &amp;amp; context&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The pattern aligns with occupational segregation observed in energy and construction value chains—installation, O&amp;amp;M, and field roles skew male, while segments with larger proportions of project management, sales, and outreach show slightly higher female shares.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These compositional differences provide important context for wage-gap analysis in §3.3–3.5: if female workers are under-represented in the highest-paying technologies or roles, aggregate pay gaps may reflect both price effects (different pay for similar roles) and mix effects (different roles/technologies).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;visual-3-bipoc-representation-gap-vs-national-workforce-average&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Visual 3: BIPOC Representation Gap vs. National Workforce Average&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#visual-3-bipoc-representation-gap-vs-national-workforce-average&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Representation Gap (BIPOC) by Technology, percentage points (pp). This figure quantifies how BIPOC (all non-White groups combined) are represented in each clean-energy technology relative to the U.S. national workforce average. Positive values indicate over-representation (BIPOC share in that technology exceeds national average); negative values indicate under-representation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Method&#xA;BIPOC share by technology: From the USEER workforce-characteristics tables, we aggregate all non-White categories (Hispanic/Latino, Black or African American (non-Indigenous), Asian, American Indian/Alaska Native, Native Hawaiian/Pacific Islander, Two or more races). For each technology and survey sheet, we compute the mean share (%).&#xA;Baseline: From the same tables’ single-column baselines, we compute National Workforce Averages for the same race/ethnicity categories and aggregate to national BIPOC share.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Key findings&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Solar and Energy Efficiency typically exhibit smaller negative gaps or modest positive gaps, indicating BIPOC participation is closer to (or slightly above) national averages in these entry-growth segments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nuclear EPG and Natural Gas EPG generally show larger negative gaps, signaling under-representation of BIPOC workers in higher-paying, capital-intensive technologies.&#xA;Hydropower (traditional and low-impact) tends to sit near or modestly below parity, but patterns can vary by sheet/aggregation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interpretation &amp;amp; implications&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The pattern suggests pipeline segmentation: BIPOC workers are more present in installation/efficiency/front-of-meter growth roles (e.g., Solar, EE), but are under-represented in legacy, higher-wage, or licensing-intensive technologies (e.g., Nuclear, Natural Gas).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Where the gap is negative and large, the sector likely faces barriers to entry and advancement (credentialing, prior experience screens, union access pathways, or geographic clustering). These are priority areas for equity interventions (e.g., apprenticeships, credential bridging, targeted recruitment, and sponsorship/mentorship).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Emoji can be enabled in a Hugo project in a number of ways. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity &amp; Workforce Equity - 1-2</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_2_clean_energy_workforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_2_clean_energy_workforce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;demographic-composition-of-the-clean-energy-workforce&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Demographic Composition of the Clean Energy Workforce&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#demographic-composition-of-the-clean-energy-workforce&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-1-raceethnicity-distribution-by-technology-stacked-bar-with-labels&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Visual 1: Race/Ethnicity Distribution by Technology (Stacked Bar with Labels)&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#visual-1-raceethnicity-distribution-by-technology-stacked-bar-with-labels&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis presents the baseline demographic composition of the clean energy workforce across selected technologies. A stacked bar chart was constructed to display the proportional representation of major racial and ethnic groups within key technologies, including Solar, Wind, Nuclear, Natural Gas, Hydropower (low-impact and traditional), and Energy Efficiency. The results reveal clear disparities across technologies:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pay Gap Analysis within Sustainability and Climate-Related Fields - 1-3</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_3_pay-gap-analysis-within-sustainability-and-climate-related-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_3_pay-gap-analysis-within-sustainability-and-climate-related-fields/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pay-gap-analysis-within-sustainability-and-climate-related-fields&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Pay Gap Analysis within Sustainability and Climate-Related Fields&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#pay-gap-analysis-within-sustainability-and-climate-related-fields&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this section is to measure wage disparities among different demographic groups (e.g., BIPOC vs. White, Male vs. Female) within the clean energy workforce. The analysis seeks to identify whether pay gaps exist and to determine which groups are most disadvantaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methodology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Sources&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;U.S. Energy &amp;amp; Employment Report (USEER): Median wage by demographic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS): Wage distributions by occupation and demographic group.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Department of Energy (DOE) reports on wage equity and workforce representation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Processing&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Evolution of Gender Pay Gaps - 1.4</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_4_temporal-evolution-of-gender-pay-gaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_4_temporal-evolution-of-gender-pay-gaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This section examines the evolution of gender pay gaps over multiple years across selected U.S. states. By analyzing longitudinal trends, we aim to determine whether disparities have narrowed or widened, and to what extent state-level policies or labor market dynamics may have influenced these patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shrinking Gaps&#xA;In California (CA) and New York (NY), gender pay gaps were relatively high in 2018. However, both states demonstrated a marked reduction by 2023. This suggests that recent policy interventions promoting pay equity, combined with labor market shifts in urban centers, have begun to yield measurable improvements in wage fairness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Volatile Trends&#xA;Texas (TX) and Florida (FL) displayed less consistent progress. Their pay gap trajectories followed a “decline-then-rebound” pattern: an initial reduction in disparities was observed, but later years saw the gap widen again. Such fluctuations may reflect uneven implementation of workplace equity initiatives, industry-specific shocks, or variations in labor force participation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Steady Convergence&#xA;Washington (WA) exhibited a relatively stable and consistent narrowing of the pay gap over the observed period. The gradual convergence toward the national average indicates steady improvement, with fewer reversals compared to more volatile states.&#xA;Overall, the time-series analysis reveals three archetypal patterns: (1) states with sustained improvement (CA, NY), (2) states with unstable or cyclical changes (TX, FL), and (3) states with gradual but steady convergence (WA). These findings highlight the importance of local labor market structures and policy frameworks in shaping long-term pay equity outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Energy technology mix&#xA;States exhibit pronounced heterogeneity in technology composition. Fossil-heavy states retain sizable Natural Gas and Coal job footprints, while coastal and high-renewables states show elevated Solar and Wind activity. These structural differences help explain geographic variation in labor demand, skill requirements, and subsequent pay-gap dynamics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hiring difficulty&#xA;States with rapid renewable buildout or transmission upgrades often report higher Very/Somewhat difficult hiring shares, especially in installation, linework, and specialized electrical roles. This suggests targeted apprenticeship and credential-bridging programs could relieve bottlenecks while improving equity outcomes.&#xA;The state-by-technology and state-by-industry matrices provide a structural lens for the pay-gap results: (i) where the occupational mix skews toward high-credential, high-wage roles with low female/BIPOC representation, gaps tend to widen; (ii) diversified states see flatter disparities overall, though Management/Professional roles can still harbor significant gaps. These patterns motivate state-specific workforce strategies rather than a one-size-fits-all approach.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- tags = [&#xA;    &#34;hugo&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;markdown&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;css&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;html&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;shortcodes&#34;,&#xA;]&#xA;categories = [&#xA;    &#34;theme demo&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;syntax&#34;,&#xA;] --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Hugo ships with several [Built-in Shortcodes](https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#use-hugos-built-in-shortcodes) for rich content, along with a [Privacy Config](https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/) and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conteúdo Rico</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_4_temporal-evolution-of-gender-pay-gaps.pt_br/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_4_temporal-evolution-of-gender-pay-gaps.pt_br/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- O Hugo vem com vários [Shortcodes Internos](https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#use-hugos-built-in-shortcodes) para conteúdo rico, assim como uma [Configuração de Privacidade](https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/) e uma gama de Shortcodes simples que permitem embutir versões estáticas e sem JS de várias de redes sociais.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;## Shortcode do YouTube com privacidade melhorada&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZJthWmvUzzc?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;---&#xA;&#xA;## Shortcode do Twitter&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Owl bet you&amp;#39;ll lose this staring contest 🦉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/eJh4f2zncC&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/eJh4f2zncC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML and CSS only tabs</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_2_clean_energy_workforce.md.pt_br/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_2_clean_energy_workforce.md.pt_br/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;shortcodes&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Shortcodes&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#shortcodes&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- O seguinte conteúdo:&#xA;&#xA;```markdown&#xA;{{&lt; tabgroup &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; tab name=&#34;Hello&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;Hello World!&#xA;{{&lt; /tab &gt;}}&#xA;&#xA;{{&lt; tab name=&#34;Goodbye&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;Goodbye Everybody!&#xA;{{&lt; /tab &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; /tabgroup &gt;}}&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;Irá gerar:&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tabs tabs-left&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;  .tabs input#tab-0-0:checked ~ .tab-content-0-0 {&#xA;    display: block;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;tab-input&#34; name=&#34;tab-select-0&#34; id=&#34;tab-0-0&#34; checked/&gt;&#xA;&lt;label for=&#34;tab-0-0&#34; class=&#34;tab-label&#34;&gt;Hello&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tab-content tab-content-0-0&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Hello World!&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;  .tabs input#tab-0-1:checked ~ .tab-content-0-1 {&#xA;    display: block;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;tab-input&#34; name=&#34;tab-select-0&#34; id=&#34;tab-0-1&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;label for=&#34;tab-0-1&#34; class=&#34;tab-label&#34;&gt;Goodbye&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tab-content tab-content-0-1&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Goodbye Everybody!&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;## Alinhamento à direita&#xA;&#xA;Você também pode alinhas as tabs à direita:&#xA;&#xA;```markdown&#xA;{{&lt; tabgroup align=&#34;right&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; tab name=&#34;Hello&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;Hello World!&#xA;{{&lt; /tab &gt;}}&#xA;&#xA;{{&lt; tab name=&#34;Goodbye&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;Goodbye Everybody!&#xA;{{&lt; /tab &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; /tabgroup &gt;}}&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;Obtendo o seguinte resultado:&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tabs tabs-right&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;  .tabs input#tab-1-0:checked ~ .tab-content-1-0 {&#xA;    display: block;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;tab-input&#34; name=&#34;tab-select-1&#34; id=&#34;tab-1-0&#34; checked/&gt;&#xA;&lt;label for=&#34;tab-1-0&#34; class=&#34;tab-label&#34;&gt;Hello&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tab-content tab-content-1-0&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Hello World!&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;  .tabs input#tab-1-1:checked ~ .tab-content-1-1 {&#xA;    display: block;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;tab-input&#34; name=&#34;tab-select-1&#34; id=&#34;tab-1-1&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;label for=&#34;tab-1-1&#34; class=&#34;tab-label&#34;&gt;Goodbye&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tab-content tab-content-1-1&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Goodbye Everybody!&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;## Conteúdo Markdown&#xA;&#xA;Qualquer conteúdo Markdown válido pode ser usado dentro das tabs:&#xA;&#xA;````markdown&#xA;{{&lt; tabgroup align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;code&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; tab name=&#34;Ruby&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;&#xA;```ruby&#xA;puts &#39;Hello&#39;&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;{{&lt; /tab &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; tab name=&#34;Python&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;&#xA;```python&#xA;print(&#39;Hello&#39;)&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;{{&lt; /tab &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; tab name=&#34;JavaScript&#34; &gt;}}&#xA;&#xA;```js&#xA;console.log(&#34;Hello&#34;);&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;{{&lt; /tab &gt;}}&#xA;{{&lt; /tabgroup &gt;}}&#xA;````&#xA;&#xA;Assim você obterá o seguinte resultado:&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tabs tabs-code tabs-right&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;  .tabs input#tab-2-0:checked ~ .tab-content-2-0 {&#xA;    display: block;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;tab-input&#34; name=&#34;tab-select-2&#34; id=&#34;tab-2-0&#34; checked/&gt;&#xA;&lt;label for=&#34;tab-2-0&#34; class=&#34;tab-label&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tab-content tab-content-2-0&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34; data-lang=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;  .tabs input#tab-2-1:checked ~ .tab-content-2-1 {&#xA;    display: block;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;tab-input&#34; name=&#34;tab-select-2&#34; id=&#34;tab-2-1&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;label for=&#34;tab-2-1&#34; class=&#34;tab-label&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tab-content tab-content-2-1&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;  .tabs input#tab-2-2:checked ~ .tab-content-2-2 {&#xA;    display: block;&#xA;  }&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;tab-input&#34; name=&#34;tab-select-2&#34; id=&#34;tab-2-2&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;label for=&#34;tab-2-2&#34; class=&#34;tab-label&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/label&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;tab-content tab-content-2-2&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34; data-lang=&#34;js&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Hello&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Nesse exemplo, `style=&#34;code&#34;` faz com que o resultado seja mais agradável quando conteúdo é puramente blocos de código. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texto de Exemplo</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_3_pay-gap-analysis-within-sustainability-and-climate-related-fields.pt_br/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/posts/1_3_pay-gap-analysis-within-sustainability-and-climate-related-fields.pt_br/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de pectora summo. Redit teque digerit hominumque toris verebor lumina non cervice subde tollit usus habet Arctonque, furores quas nec ferunt. Quoque montibus nunc caluere tempus inhospita parcite confusaque translucet patri vestro qui optatis lumine cognoscere flos nubis! Fronde ipsamque patulos Dryopen deorum.&#xA;&#xA;1. Exierant elisi ambit vivere dedere&#xA;2. Duce pollice&#xA;3. Eris modo&#xA;4. Spargitque ferrea quos palude&#xA;&#xA;Rursus nulli murmur; hastile inridet ut ab gravi sententia! Nomine potitus silentia flumen, sustinet placuit petis in dilapsa erat sunt. Atria tractus malis.&#xA;&#xA;1. Comas hunc haec pietate fetum procerum dixit&#xA;2. Post torum vates letum Tiresia&#xA;3. Flumen querellas&#xA;4. Arcanaque montibus omnes&#xA;5. Quidem et&#xA;&#xA;# Vagus elidunt&#xA;&#xA;&lt;svg class=&#34;canon&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; overflow=&#34;visible&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 496 373&#34; height=&#34;373&#34; width=&#34;496&#34;&gt;&lt;g fill=&#34;none&#34;&gt;&lt;path stroke=&#34;#000&#34; stroke-width=&#34;.75&#34; d=&#34;M.599 372.348L495.263 1.206M.312.633l494.95 370.853M.312 372.633L247.643.92M248.502.92l246.76 370.566M330.828 123.869V1.134M330.396 1.134L165.104 124.515&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path stroke=&#34;#ED1C24&#34; stroke-width=&#34;.75&#34; d=&#34;M275.73 41.616h166.224v249.05H275.73zM54.478 41.616h166.225v249.052H54.478z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path stroke=&#34;#000&#34; stroke-width=&#34;.75&#34; d=&#34;M.479.375h495v372h-495zM247.979.875v372&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;ellipse cx=&#34;498.729&#34; cy=&#34;177.625&#34; rx=&#34;.75&#34; ry=&#34;1.25&#34;&gt;&lt;/ellipse&gt;&lt;ellipse cx=&#34;247.229&#34; cy=&#34;377.375&#34; rx=&#34;.75&#34; ry=&#34;1.25&#34;&gt;&lt;/ellipse&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;&#xA;[The Van de Graaf Canon](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canons_of_page_construction#Van_de_Graaf_canon)&#xA;&#xA;## Mane refeci capiebant unda mulcebat&#xA;&#xA;Victa caducifer, malo vulnere contra dicere aurato, ludit regale, voca! Retorsit colit est profanae esse virescere furit nec; iaculi matertera et visa est, viribus. Divesque creatis, tecta novat collumque vulnus est, parvas. **Faces illo pepulere** tempus adest. Tendit flamma, ab opes virum sustinet, sidus sequendo urbis.&#xA;&#xA;Iubar proles corpore raptos vero auctor imperium; sed et huic: manus caeli Lelegas tu lux. Verbis obstitit intus oblectamina fixis linguisque ausus sperare Echionides cornuaque tenent clausit possit. Omnia putatur. Praeteritae refert ausus; ferebant e primus lora nutat, vici quae mea ipse. Et iter nil spectatae vulnus haerentia iuste et exercebat, sui et.&#xA;&#xA;Eurytus Hector, materna ipsumque ut Politen, nec, nate, ignari, vernum cohaesit sequitur. Vel **mitis temploque** vocatus, inque alis, _oculos nomen_ non silvis corpore coniunx ne displicet illa. Crescunt non unus, vidit visa quantum inmiti flumina mortis facto sic: undique a alios vincula sunt iactata abdita! Suspenderat ego fuit tendit: luna, ante urbem Propoetides **parte**.&#xA;&#xA; --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Follow us, @HydraEarth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pei-hydraearth.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing to see here&amp;hellip; Move along!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
